<quizdata>
<question><title>STRUCTURE OF THE ATMOSPHERE</title>
<line>The atmosphere consists of several concentric layers, each displaying its own unique characteristics.</line>
<line>Each layer is known as a <q>sphere</q>.</line>
<line>Between each of these is an imaginary boundary, known as a <q>pause</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>THE SPHERES OF THE ATMOSPHERE</title>
<line>In order from lowest to highest, the spheres of the atmosphere are:</line>
<line><q>troposphere stratosphere mesosphere thermosphere</q></line>
</question>

<question><title>PHYSIOLOGICAL ZONES OF THE ATMOSPHERE</title>
<line>The <q>efficient</q> zone extends from sea level to <q>10000</q> feet. It provides aircrews with a near-ideal physiological environment.</line>
<line>The <q>deficient</q> zone of the atmosphere ranges from 10000 feet at its base to <q>50000</q> feet at its highest point.</line>
<line>Extending from 50000 feet and continuing to the outer fringes of the atmosphere, the <q>space equivalent</q> zone is totally hostile to human life.</line>
</question>

<question><title>TYPES OF HYPOXIA</title>
<line>There are four major types of hypoxia: <q>hypoxic</q>, <q>hypemic</q>, <q>stagnant</q>, and <q>histotoxic</q></line>
</question>

<question><title>HYPOXIC HYPOXIA</title>
<line>Hypoxic hypoxia occurs when <q>not enough oxygen is in the air</q> or when <q>decreasing atmospheric pressures</q> prevent the diffusion of O2 from the lungs to the bloodstream.</line>
<line>Aviation personnel are most likely to encounter this type <q>at altitude</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>HYPEMIC HYPOXIA</title>
<line>Hypemic, or anemic, hypoxia is caused by <q>a reduction in the oxygen carrying capacity of the blood</q>.</line>
<line><q>Anemia</q> and <q>blood loss</q> are the most common causes of this type.</line>
</question>

<question><title>STAGNANT HYPOXIA</title>
<line>In stagnant hypoxia, the oxygen-carrying capacity of the blood is adequate but <q>circulation is inadequate</q>.</line>
<line>This can be induced when a crew member experiences <q>extreme gravitational forces</q>, disrupting blood flow and causing the blood to stagnate.</line>
</question>

<question><title>HISTOTOXIC HYPOXIA</title>
<line>This type results when there is <q>interference</q> with the use of O2 by body tissues.</line>
<line><q>Alcohol</q>, <q>narcotics</q>, and certain poisons such as cyanide interefere with the cells' ability to use an adequate supply of oxygen.</line>
</question>

<question><title>PHYSIOLOGICAL ALTITUDE</title>
<line>Cigarette smoking significantly increases the amount of CO carried by the hemoglobin of RBCs; thus, it reduces the capacity of the blood to combine wiht oxygen. This raises the smoker's physiological altitude by <q>5000</q> feet.</line>
<line>An individual who has consumed 1 ounce of alcohol may have a physiological altitude of <q>2000</q> feet.</line>
</question>

<question><title>STAGES OF HYPOXIC HYPOXIA</title>
<line>There are four stages of hypoxic hypoxia: <q>indifferent compensatory disturbance critical</q>.</line>
<line>Mild hypoxia in the indifferent stage causes night vision to deteriorate at about <q>4000</q> feet.</line>
<line>Indifferent stage altitude: 0 to <q>10000</q> feet</line>
<line>Compensatory stage altitude: 10000 to <q>15000</q> feet</line>
<line>Disturbance stage altitude: 15000 to <q>20000</q> feet</line>
<line>Compensatory stage altitude: 20000 to <q>25000</q> feet</line>
</question>

<question><title>STRESS</title>
<line>Stress is the <q>nonspecific response</q> of the body to any demand placed upon it.</line>
<line>A stressor is any stimulus or event that <q>requires an individual to adjust or adapt</q> in some way.</line>
<line>Stressors may be <q>psychosocial</q>, <q>environmental</q>, <q>physiological</q>, or <q>cognitive</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>PHYSIOLOGICAL (SELF-IMPOSED) STRESSORS</title>
<line><q>drugs exhaustion alcohol tobacco hypoglycemia</q></line>
</question>

<question><title>FATIGUE</title>
<line>Fatigue is the state of <q>feeling tired weary or sleepy</q> that results from prolonged mental of physical work, extended periods of anxiety, exposure to harsh environments, or loss of sleep.</line>
<line>The types of fatigue are <q>acute</q>, <q>chronic</q>, and <q>motivational exhaustion</q> or burnout.</line>
</question>

<question><title>VISUAL DEFICIENCIES</title>
<line>Important eye problems related to degraded visual acuity and depth perception include <q>myopia</q>, <q>hyperopia</q>, <q>astigmatism</q>, <q>presbyopia</q> and <q>retinal rivalry</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>ANATOMY AND PHYSIOLOGY OF THE EYE</title>
<line>When light from an object enters the eye, it first passes through the <q>cornea</q>. This is a circular, transparent <q>protective tissue</q> that projects forward.</line>
<line>Once light travels through the cornea, it enters the <q>pupil</q>, which is the <q>opening</q> in the center of the <q>iris</q>.</line>
<line>The iris is the round, colored membrane of the eye surrounding the pupil.</line>
<line>Once the light travels through the pupil, it will strike the <q>lens</q>, which is a transparent, biconvex membrane. This refracts the light onto the <q>retina</q>. </line>
<line>Once light stimulates the retina, it produces a chemical change within the photoreceptor cells. When the chemical change occurs, nerve impulses are stimulated and transmitted to the brain via the optic nerve.</line>
</question>

<question><title>NIGHT VISION</title>
<line>For night vision to take place, rhodopsin must build up in the rods. The average time required to gain the greatest sensitivity is <q>30</q> to <q>45</q> minutes in a dark environment.</line>
</question>

<question><title>TYPES OF VISION</title>
<line>The three types of vision (viewing periods) associated with Army aviation are <q>photopic</q>, <q>mesopic</q>, and <q>scotopic</q>.</line>
<line>The day blind spot covers an area of 5.5 to 7.5 degrees. It is located about <q>15</q> degrees from the fovea and originates where the optic nerve attaches to the retina.</line>
<line>The night blind spot involves an area from <q>5</q> to <q>10</q> degrees wide <q>in the center</q> of the visual field.</line>
</question>

<question><title>BINOCULAR CUES</title>
<line>In the flight environment, most distances outside the cockpit are so great that the binocular cues are <q>of little if any value</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>MONOCULAR CUES</title>
<line>Several monocular cues aid in distance estimation and depth perception. They can be remembered by the acronym <q>gram</q>.</line>
<line> * G: <q>geometric perspective</q>: the types can be remembered by the acronym <q>lav</q>.</line>
<line>  - L: <q>linear perspective</q></line>
<line>  - A: <q>apparent foreshortening</q></line>
<line>  - V: <q>Vertical position in the field</q></line>
<line> * R: <q>Retinal Image Size</q>: the types can be remembered by the acronym <q>kito</q></line>
<line>  - K: <q>Known size of objects</q></line>
<line>  - I: <q>increasing or decreasing size</q></line>
<line>  - T: <q>terrestrial association</q></line>
<line>  - O: <q>overlapping</q></line>
<line> * A: <q>Aerial perspective</q>: the types can be remembered by their initials <q>flp</q></line>
<line>  - F: <q>Fading of colors or shades</q></line>
<line>  - L: <q>loss of detail or texture</q></line>
<line>  - P: <q>position of light source and direction of shadow</q></line>
<line> * M: <q>Motion Parallax</q> is the most important monocular cue to depth perception</line>
</question>

<question><title>SPATIAL DISORIENTATION</title>
<line>Spatial disorientation is an individual's inability to determine his or her <q>position</q>, <q>attitude</q>, and <q>motion</q> relative to the <q>surface of the earth</q> or significant objects; for example trees, poles, or buildings at a hover.</line>
</question>

<question><title>TYPES OF SPATIAL DISORIENTATION</title>
<line>Type I: <q>unrecognized</q>. This is the most dangerous type of disorientation.</line>
<line>Type II: <q>recognized</q></line>
<line>Type III: <q>Incapacitating</q>. This is not fatal if the copilot can gain control of the aircraft.</line>
</question>

<question><title>EQUILIBRIUM MAINTENANCE</title>
<line>Three sensory systems--the <q>visual</q>, <q>vestibular</q>, and <q>proprioceptive</q> systems--are especially important in maintaining equilibrium and balance.</line>
<line>Of the three sensory systems, the <q>visual</q> system is the most important.</line>
<line>The <q>inner ear</q> contains the vestibular system.</line>
<line>The proprioceptive system is what led to the term "<q>seat of the pants</q>" flying</line>
</question>

<question><title>VESTIBULAR SYSTEM</title>
<line>The inner ear contains the vestibular system. Each vestibular apparatus consists of two distinct structures: the <q>semicircular canals</q> and the vestibule proper, which contains the <q>otolith organs</q>.</line>
<line>The semicircular canals detect changes in <q>angular</q> acceleration and deceleration.</line>
<line>The otolith organs detect changes in <q>linear</q> acceleration and deceleration.</line>
</question>

<question><title>VISUAL ILLUSIONS</title>
<line>There are <q>12</q> visual illusions which can be remembered by the mnemonic <q>fff crash csar</q>.</line>
<line>F: <q>false horizon                </q></line>
<line>F: <q>fascination</q></line>
<line>F: <q>flicker vertigo              </q></line>
<line>C: <q>confusion with ground lights </q></line>
<line>R: <q>relative motion              </q></line>
<line>A: <q>altered planes of reference  </q></line>
<line>S: <q>size distance                </q></line>
<line>H: <q>height depth perception      </q></line>
<line>C: <q>crater                       </q></line>
<line>S: <q>structural                   </q></line>
<line>A: <q>autokinesis                  </q></line>
<line>R: <q>reversible perspective       </q></line>
</question>

<question><title>FALSE HORIZON</title>
<line>False horizon occurs when the aviator confuses <q>cloud formations</q> with the horizon.</line>
</question>

<question><title>FASCINATION / FIXATION</title>
<line>Fascination, or fixation, can be separated into two categories: <q>task saturation</q> and <q>target fixation</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>FLICKER VERTIGO</title>
<line>Flicker vertigo is technically not an illusion. It may be created by interrupting direct sunlight at a rate of <q>4</q> to <q>20</q> hertz.</line>
</question>

<question><title>CONFUSION WITH GROUND LIGHTS</title>
<line>Confusion with ground lights occurs when an aviator mistakes ground lights for <q>stars</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>RELATIVE MOTION ILLUSION</title>
<line>Relative motion illusion is the falsely perceived self motion <q>in relation to another object</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>ALTERED PLANES OF REFERENCE</title>
<line>In altered planes of reference, the pilot has an inaccurate sense of altitude, attitude, or flight-path position in relation to an object so <q>great in size</q> that the object <q>becomes the new plane of reference</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>SIZE DISTANCE ILLUSION</title>
<line>The size distance illusion is the false perception of distance from an object or the ground created when a crew member misinterprets an unfamiliar object's size to be <q>the same as an object</q> that he or she is <q>accustomed to viewing</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>HEIGHT DEPTH PERCEPTION</title>
<line>The height depth perception illusion is due to a <q>lack of sufficient visual cues</q> and causes an aircrew member to lose depth perception.</line>
</question>

<question><title>CRATER ILLUSION</title>
<line>The crater illusion occurs when aircrew members land at night and the light is too far under the nose. This will cause the illusion of landing with <q>up sloping terrain in all directions</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>STRUCTURAL ILLUSION</title>
<line>Structural illusions are caused by the effects of <q>visual obscurants</q> which <q>refract images in misleading ways</q>.</line>
</question>

<question><title>AUTOKINESIS</title>
<line>Autokinesis occurs at night when ambient visual cues are minimal and a small dim light is seen against a dark background. After about <q>6</q> to <q>12</q> seconds of visually fixating on the light, one perceives <q>movement</q> at up to <q>20</q> degrees in any direction though there is no actual displacement of the light.</line>
</question>

<question><title>REVERSIBLE PERSPECTIVE</title>
<line>Reversible perspective illusion is the illusion that another aircraft is <q>moving away</q> when actually it is <q>approaching</q>. It is often experienced when the two aircraft are moving on a <q>parallel course</q>.</line>
</question>
</quizdata>